Guide to the Eugene O'Neill Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Carlotta Monterey O'Neill Correspondence, 1953-1965; Series II; 8.8; (23 boxes)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Cadwalader, Wickersham & Taft
      - Correspondence, 1957 Jun-Sep (Box 17, Folder 413)
      - Correspondence, 1957 Oct-58 Aug (Box 17, Folder 414)
      - Correspondence, 1958 Sep-Dec (Box 18, Folder 415)
      - Correspondence, 1959 Jan-Aug (Box 18, Folder 416)
      - Correspondence, 1959 Sep-60 Jul (Box 18, Folder 417)
      - Correspondence, 1960 Aug-Sep (Box 18, Folder 418)
      - Correspondence, 1960 Oct-61 Mar (Box 18, Folder 419)
      - Correspondence, 1961 Apr-Jul (Box 18, Folder 420)
      - Correspondence, 1961 Aug-62 Feb (Box 18, Folder 421)
      - Correspondence, 1962 Apr-May (Box 18, Folder 422)
      - Correspondence, 1962 Jun-Jul (Box 18, Folder 423)
      - Correspondence, 1962 Aug-Oct (Box 18, Folder 424)
      - Correspondence, 1963 Jan-Mar (Box 18, Folder 425)
      - Correspondence, 1963 Apr-May (Box 18, Folder 426)
      - Correspondence, 1963 Jun-Jul (Box 18, Folder 427)
      - Correspondence, 1963 Aug-Oct (Box 18, Folder 428)
      - Correspondence, 1963 Nov-64 Apr (Box 18, Folder 429)
      - Correspondence, 1964 May-Aug (Box 18, Folder 430)
      - Correspondence, 1964 Sep-65 Mar (Box 18, Folder 431)
    - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, 1954-62 (Box 19, Folder 432-433)
    - Capalbo, Carmen, 1954-56 (Box 19, Folder 434)
      Includes letters also signed by
      Stanley Chase.
    - Cargill, Oscar, 1962 Jan 17 (Box 19, Folder 435)
    - Carl Strakosch, 1955-59 (Box 19, Folder 436)
    - Carlton House (New York, N.Y.), 1961-65, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 437)
    - Carpenter, Frederic Ives, 1962 Jan 30 (Box 19, Folder 438)
    - Chase, Ilka, 1953, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 439)
    - Chase, Stanley, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 440)
      See also: Carmen Capalbo, box 19, folder 434
    - Chinoy, Helen Krich, 1963 Mar 24 (Box 19, Folder 441)
    - Circle in the Square (Theater), 1956-66, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 442-443)
      Includes letters from Leigh Connell,
      Theodore Mann, and José Quintero.
    - Clayes, Stanley A., 1960 (Box 19, Folder 444)
    - Cleveland Public Library, 1963 May 15 (Box 19, Folder 445)
    - Coe, Richard L., 1957 (Box 19, Folder 446)
    - Cohen, Alexander H., 1956 Apr 3 (Box 19, Folder 447)
    - Colton, Edward E., 1956-62 (Box 19, Folder 448)
    - Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc., 1955-64 (Box 19, Folder 449)
    - Columbia University, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 450)
    - Connell, Leigh, 1960-62, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 451)
      See also: Circle in the Square (Theater), box 19, folders 442-443
      See also: José Quintero, box 27, folder 658
      See also: Drafts of letters, shorthand, in notebook #1, box 37, folder 828
    - Crawford, Cheryl
    - Curtis Brown Ltd., 1962 Sep 27 (Box 19, Folder 452)
    - "D" general, 1955-65, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 453)
    - Dag Hammarskjöld Foundation, 1961-65 (Box 19, Folder 454-457)
    - Davenport, William Henry, 1962-63 (Box 20, Folder 458)
    - Davis, Blevins, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 459)
    - Day, Cyrus Lawrence, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 460)
    - Deeter, Jasper, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 461)
    - Deraney, Beverley R., 1964 (Box 20, Folder 462)
    - Dillman, Bradford, 1956 Nov 9 (Box 20, Folder 463)
    - Dodson, Eleanor, 1953-64, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 464-465)
      Letter dated 1962 Jan 1 encloses
      eleven photographs of Dodson's house.
    - Dolmetsch, Carl R., 1964 Dec 5 (Box 20, Folder 466)
    - Donovan, Vincent C., 1953-60 (Box 20, Folder 467)
    - D'Orazio, Julie, 1955-64, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 468)
    - Douglas, Kirk, 1961 Aug 8 (Box 20, Folder 469)
    - Douglas, Reid, 1957, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 470)
    - Douglas L. Elliman & Co., 1958-64, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 471)
    - Doyle, Len, 1956 Nov 28 (Box 20, Folder 472)
    - Dramatiska teatern (Stockholm, Sweden), 1963 Jun 27 (Box 20, Folder 473)
    - Dramatists Play Service (New York, N.Y.), 1954-61 (Box 20, Folder 474)
    - Driver, Tom Faw, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 475)
    - Dunnock, Mildred, 1956, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 476)
    - "E" general, 1953-62, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 477)
    - Edizioni Enrico Raggio, 1953-63 (Box 20, Folder 478)
    - Eisenman, Alvin, 1957-63 (Box 20, Folder 479)
    - Ernst, Cane & Berner, 1953-55 (Box 20, Folder 480)
    - Esquire (New York, N.Y.), 1957 Jan 25 (Box 20, Folder 481)
    - Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theater Foundation, Inc., 1967 (Box 20, Folder 482)
    - "F" general, 1957, 1964, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 483)
    - Fagin, Nathan Bryllion, 1963, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 484)
    - Farberman, Harold, 1957-59 (Box 20, Folder 485)
    - Fern, Dale Edward (Box 20, Folder 486)
    - Field, Betty, 1958, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 487)
    - Fisher, William J., 1960-63 (Box 20, Folder 488)
    - Flanagan, Hallie, 1953-58 (Box 21, Folder 489)
    - Fleisher, Frederic, 1956-62, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 490)
    - Ford, John, 1953 Dec 2 (Box 21, Folder 491)
    - Fordham University, 1961 Apr 12 (Box 21, Folder 492)
    - Forest Hills Cemetery (Boston, Mass.), 1953-65 (Box 21, Folder 493)
    - Franklin Book Programs, Inc., 1957 (Box 21, Folder 494)
    - Freedley, George, 1953 Dec 7 (Box 21, Folder 495)
    - Frenz, Horst, 1961-64 (Box 21, Folder 496)
    - Frueh, Alfred Joseph, 1955-63, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 497)
    - Fryer, Robert, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 498)
    - Funke, Lewis, 1956 Jun 26 (Box 21, Folder 499)
    - "G" general, 1955-64, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 500)
    - Gallup, Donald Clifford
      See: Yale University Library, box 35, folder 805 through box 36, folder 816
    - Geddes, Norman Bel, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 501)
    - Gelb, Arthur Gelb, Barbara, 1957-62 (Box 21, Folder 502-503)
    - Gierow, Karl Ragnar
      - Correspondence, 1953-55 (Box 22, Folder 504)
      - Correspondence, 1956 Jan-Feb (Box 22, Folder 505)
      - Correspondence, 1956 Mar-Aug (Box 22, Folder 506)
        Letter dated 1956 Aug 3 encloses
        photograph of Gierow, Eric
        Linklater, and Gierow's wife.
      - Correspondence, 1956 Sep-57 Mar (Box 22, Folder 507)
      - Correspondence, 1957 Apr-58 Sep (Box 22, Folder 508)
      - Correspondence, 1958 Oct-59 (Box 22, Folder 509)
      - Correspondence, 1960-61 Jun (Box 22, Folder 510)
      - Correspondence, 1961 Aug-Nov (Box 22, Folder 511)
      - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 512)
      - Correspondence, 1963 Jan-May (Box 22, Folder 513)
      - Correspondence, 1963-65, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 514)
        Letter dated 1963 Jun 5 encloses
        program and two photographs from Desire Under the Elms.
    - Gray, Wood, 1957 Jul 17 (Box 22, Folder 515)
    - "H" general, 1954-62, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 516)
      See also: Isabel Halliburton, oversize, box 141, folder 2504
    - Hakusuisha Publishers, 1957-63 (Box 22, Folder 517)
    - Hammarskjöld, Dag, 1955-60 (Box 23, Folder 518-519)
    - Hanson, Lars, 1956 Feb 21 (Box 23, Folder 520)
      See also: Inga Tidblad, box 33, folder 764
    - Harcourt, Brace & Company, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 521)
    - Harvard College Library, 1958-59 (Box 23, Folder 522)
    - Haskins & Sells, 1964 May 6 (Box 23, Folder 523)
    - Havre, Paralee, 1953-59, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 524-526)
      Letter postmarked 1959 Dec 23
      encloses handkerchief.
    - Hayes, Helen, [1963?] Sep 12 (Box 23, Folder 527)
    - Heidt, Joseph, 1954, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 528)
    - Henrikson, Anders, 1958 Oct 23 (Box 23, Folder 529)
    - Hewes, Henry, 1958-64 (Box 23, Folder 530)
    - Heyward, Dorothy, 1957 May 5 (Box 23, Folder 531)
    - Hirsch, Gerhard, 1955-64 (Box 23, Folder 532)
    - Hitotsubashi Daigaku, 1961 Sep 26 (Box 23, Folder 533)
    - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc., 1968 Aug 29 (Box 23, Folder 534)
    - House of Books, Ltd. (New York, N.Y.), 1963 Aug 13 (Box 23, Folder 535)
    - Hubler, Edward, 1953 Dec 21 (Box 23, Folder 536)
    - "I" general, 1953, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 537)
    - Ibérica, 1956 Apr 30 (Box 23, Folder 538)
    - Inoué, Sôji, 1954-63, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 539-540)
      See also: Eiji Ishida, box 23, folder 542
    - International Theatre Institute. Japan Center, 1960 May 25 (Box 23, Folder 541)
    - Ishida, Eiji, 1953, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 542)
    - "J" general, 1954-65, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 543)
    - Jonathan Cape Limited, 1955-62 (Box 23, Folder 544)
    - Jones, Robert Edmond, 1953, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 545)
    - Jugoslovenska autorska agencija, 1959 Oct 20 (Box 23, Folder 546)
    - "K" general, 1955-62, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 547)
    - Kanin, Garson, 1956 Jun 14 (Box 23, Folder 548)
    - Kaye, Benjamin M., 1961 (Box 23, Folder 549)
      Includes galley proof of Theresa
      Helburn's A Wayward Quest: The Autobiography of Theresa Helburn.
    - Kemp, F. Roy, 1954-59 (Box 24, Folder 550)
      Letter dated 1954 May 14 encloses
      four photographs of Kemp's children
      and wife. Undated note sent on back
      of photograph of baby.
    - Kerr, Walter, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 551)
    - Kinne, Wisner Payne, 1954-57 (Box 24, Folder 552-553)
      Includes two letters from Barbara
      Kinne. Letter dated 1955 May 16
      encloses five photographs of Barbara,
      dogs, and house. Letter dated 1957
      May 7 encloses two photographs of
      Barbara and son.
    - Kitamura, Kihachi, 1953, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 554)
    - Kongelige Teater (Denmark), 1956, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 555)
    - Konopak, Faron, 1962-63 (Box 24, Folder 556)
    - Kozol, Harry L., 1953-59 (Box 24, Folder 557)
    - Kramm, Joseph, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 558)
    - Krause, David, 1962 Jul 13 (Box 24, Folder 559)
    - Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1954-61 (Box 24, Folder 560-561)
    - "L" general, 1953-64, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 562)
    - Lambs (New York, N.Y.), 1953 Dec 1 (Box 24, Folder 563)
    - Landau, Ely, 1960-65, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 564-565)
    - Leachman, Cloris, 1959 May 8 (Box 24, Folder 566)
    - Lee, Kaye Lee, Man, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 567)
    - Levine, Joseph E., 1964 Nov 30 (Box 24, Folder 568)
      See also: Theodore Mann, box 25, folder 587
    - Levy, Marvin David, 1960-65 (Box 24, Folder 569-570)
    - Lewis, Alfred Allen, 1961-63 (Box 24, Folder 571)
    - Library of Congress. Manuscript Division, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 572)
    - Lindsay, Howard, 1959 Jun 4 (Box 24, Folder 573)
    - Luce, Claire, 1960 Jan 27 (Box 24, Folder 574)
    - Lumet, Sidney, 1961 Sep 11 (Box 24, Folder 575)
    - "M" general, 1956-65, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 576-577)
    - McCormick, Myron, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 578)
    - McGee, Harold, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 579)
    - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 580)
    - MacKaye, Percy, 1953 Nov 28 (Box 25, Folder 581)
    - McMaster, Anew, 1958 Jan 15 (Box 25, Folder 582)
    - Magaldi, Sábato, 1959-60 (Box 25, Folder 583)
    - Mallet, Thierry, 1957-63, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 584)
      Undated note on photograph of Mallet
      and his grandson.
    - Mamoulian, Rouben, 1953 Dec 1 (Box 25, Folder 585)
    - Mann, Abby, 1962 Feb 15 (Box 25, Folder 586)
    - Mann, Theodore, 1965, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 587)
      Telegram also from Joseph E. Levine.
    - Manning, Doris Manning, Robert E., Jr., 1955-63, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 588)
      Letter dated 1958 Jun 10 encloses two
      photographs of Robert.
    - Manufacturers Trust Company, 1954-56 (Box 25, Folder 589)
      See also: Series IV, Personal Papers, Financial and Legal Material, box 99, folder 1645 through box 101, folder 1664; box 103, folder 1710 through box 104, folder 1716
    - March, Fredric March, Florence, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 590)
      See also: Austin and Noyes, box 16, folder 376
    - March of Dimes Birth Defects Foundation, 1965 Apr 19 (Box 25, Folder 591)
    - Marie Magdaleine of Sion, Sister, 1956-63 (Box 25, Folder 592)
    - Mayfield, John S., 1960-61 (Box 25, Folder 593)
    - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, 1961 Jul 18 (Box 25, Folder 594)
    - Middleton, George, 1955-58, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 595)
      Letter dated 1955 Jun 27 encloses
      three photostats of letters from EO
      to Middleton.
    - Mielziner, Jo, 1953-58 (Box 25, Folder 596)
    - Miner, Worthington, 1960-61 (Box 25, Folder 597)
    - Mirlas, León, 1953-64 (Box 25, Folder 598-599)
    - Mohn, Bent, 1956-57 (Box 25, Folder 600)
    - Mosheim, Grete, 1956-63 (Box 25, Folder 601)
    - Museum of the City of New York, 1954-56 (Box 25, Folder 602)
    - "N" general, 1955-61 (Box 25, Folder 603)
    - Nathan, George Jean, 1953-56 (Box 25, Folder 604)
    - National Academy of Recording Arts and Sciences (U.S.), 1964 Apr 17 (Box 25, Folder 605)
      See also: Series IV, Personal Papers, Certificates and Awards, box 89, folder 1525
    - National Broadcasting Company, Inc., 1958 Jun 18 (Box 25, Folder 606)
    - National Cultural Center, 1962 Apr 12 (Box 25, Folder 607)
    - Neergaard, Arthur Edwin, 1964, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 608)
    - New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.), 1954 Mar 4 (Box 25, Folder 609)
    - New York Public Library, 1954-60 (Box 26, Folder 610)
    - New York Telephone Company, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 611)
    - The New York Times, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 612)
    - New York University Press, 1961 Aug 31 (Box 26, Folder 613)
    - The New Yorker (New York, N.Y.), 1956 (Box 26, Folder 614)
    - News (New York, N.Y.), 1956 (Box 26, Folder 615)
    - Newsweek, 1957 May 20 (Box 26, Folder 616)
    - Nichols, Dudley, 1953-59, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 617-622)
      Includes letters also signed by Esta
      Nichols.
    - Nichols, Esta, 1960-63 (Box 26, Folder 623)
      See also: Dudley Nichols, box 26, folders 617-622
    - Norton, Elliot, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 624)
    - Nutter, McClennen & Fish, 1953-64, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 625-631)
      See also: Drafts of letters, shorthand, in notebook #3, box 37, folder 830
    - "O" general, 1954, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 632)
    - O'Casey, Eileen, [1959, 1960] (Box 27, Folder 633)
    - Oneal, John A., 1953-62 (Box 27, Folder 634)
    - Osterman, Lester, 1959 Sep 23 (Box 27, Folder 635)
    - "P" general, 1953-65 (Box 27, Folder 636)
    - Paramount Pictures Corporation, 1954-61 (Box 27, Folder 637)
    - Paton, R. Townley, 1957 Jan 18 (Box 27, Folder 638)
    - Patras, Ahmad Shah Bukhari, 1956 Mar 15 (Box 27, Folder 639)
    - Paula-Lima, Francisco Pontes de, 1961-62 (Box 27, Folder 640)
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 141,
      folder 2505
    - Paulson, Arvid, 1953-61 (Box 27, Folder 641)
    - Pell, John H. G., 1953-59 (Box 27, Folder 642-644)
    - Peter A. Juley & Son, 1963 May 1 (Box 27, Folder 645)
    - Philips, David E., 1955-56 (Box 27, Folder 646)
    - Phoenix Theatre (New York, N.Y.), 1958-64 (Box 27, Folder 647)
    - Players (Club), [1953] Nov 29 (Box 27, Folder 648)
    - Pollock, Helen Channing, 1953 Nov 28 (Box 27, Folder 649)
    - Pommer, Henry F., 1962-63 (Box 27, Folder 650)
    - Poole, Abram, 1959 Feb 5 (Box 27, Folder 651)
    - Popkin, Henry, 1962 May 14 (Box 27, Folder 652)
    - Prideaux, Tom, 1956 Aug 22 (Box 27, Folder 653)
    - Princeton University. Graduate Council, 1953 Dec 3 (Box 27, Folder 654)
    - Princeton University. Library, 1954-56 (Box 27, Folder 655)
    - Quentin, Pol, 1959 May 21 (Box 27, Folder 656)
    - Quinn, Arthur Hobson, 1953, 1954 (Box 27, Folder 657)
    - Quintero, José, 1956-62, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 658)
      Includes letter also signed by Leigh
      Connell and Theodore Mann.
    - Quo Vadis Restaurant, 1957-65, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 659-660)
    - "R" general, 1957-63, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 661)
    - RKO General, Inc., 1961 (Box 28, Folder 662)
    - Rabén & Sjögren bokförlag, 1956-60 (Box 28, Folder 663)
    - Random House (Firm), 1954-64 (Box 28, Folder 664-665)
    - Reader's Digest, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 666)
    - Redgrave, Michael, 1961, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 667)
    - Renoir, Dido Renoir, Jean, 1956 Aug 17 (Box 28, Folder 668)
    - The Repertory Theater of Lincoln Center, 1961-64 (Box 28, Folder 669)
      Letter dated 1964 Mar 18 encloses
      three photographs of exhibit
      regarding O'Neill.
    - Richard J. Madden Play Company, Inc.
      Includes correspondence with Jane
      Rubin.
      - Correspondence, 1953 Dec-54 Apr (Box 28, Folder 670)
      - Correspondence, 1954 May-Aug (Box 28, Folder 671)
      - Correspondence, 1954 Sep-55 Jun (Box 28, Folder 672)
      - Correspondence, 1955 Jul-56 Jan (Box 28, Folder 673)
      - Correspondence, 1956 Feb-Jun (Box 28, Folder 674)
      - Correspondence, 1956 Jul-Oct (Box 28, Folder 675)
      - Correspondence, 1956 Nov-57 Jan (Box 28, Folder 676)
      - Correspondence, 1957 Feb-May (Box 28, Folder 677)
      - Correspondence, 1957 Jun-Aug (Box 28, Folder 678)
      - Correspondence, 1957 Sep-Nov (Box 29, Folder 679)
      - Correspondence, 1957 Dec (Box 29, Folder 680)
      - Correspondence, 1958 Jan-Dec (Box 29, Folder 681)
      - Correspondence, 1959 Jan-Mar (Box 29, Folder 682)
      - Correspondence, 1959 Apr-Jun (Box 29, Folder 683)
      - Correspondence, 1959 Jul-Sep (Box 29, Folder 684)
      - Correspondence, 1959 Oct (Box 29, Folder 685)
      - Correspondence, 1959 Nov (Box 29, Folder 686)
      - Correspondence, 1959 Dec-60 Jan (Box 29, Folder 687)
      - Correspondence, 1960 Feb-Mar (Box 29, Folder 688)
      - Correspondence, 1960 Apr (Box 29, Folder 689)
      - Correspondence, 1960 May (Box 29, Folder 690)
      - Correspondence, 1960 Jun-Jul (Box 29, Folder 691)
      - Correspondence, 1960 Aug-Sep (Box 29, Folder 692)
      - Correspondence, 1960 Oct (Box 29, Folder 693)
      - Correspondence, 1960 Nov-Dec (Box 30, Folder 694)
      - Correspondence, 1961 Jan-Sep (Box 30, Folder 695)
      - Correspondence, 1961 Oct-Dec (Box 30, Folder 696)
      - Correspondence, 1962 Jan (Box 30, Folder 697)
      - Correspondence, 1962 Feb (Box 30, Folder 698)
      - Correspondence, 1962 Mar-Apr (Box 30, Folder 699)
      - Correspondence, 1962 May-Jun (Box 30, Folder 700)
      - Correspondence, 1962 Jul (Box 30, Folder 701)
      - Correspondence, 1962 Aug (Box 30, Folder 702)
      - Correspondence, 1962 Sep (Box 30, Folder 703)
      - Correspondence, 1962 Oct (Box 30, Folder 704)
      - Correspondence, 1962 Nov (Box 30, Folder 705)
      - Correspondence, 1962 Dec-63 Jan (Box 30, Folder 706)
      - Correspondence, 1963 May-Aug (Box 30, Folder 707)
      - Correspondence, 1964 Feb-Jul (Box 30, Folder 708)
      - Correspondence, 1964 Aug-65 Jan (Box 30, Folder 709)
      - Correspondence, 1965 Feb (Box 30, Folder 710)
      - Correspondence, 1965 Feb-Mar (Box 31, Folder 711)
      - Correspondence, 1965 Apr-68 (Box 31, Folder 712)
      - Correspondence (Box 31, Folder 713)
    - Richards, Stanley, 1956 Jan 11 (Box 31, Folder 714)
    - Ritter, Thelma, 1957 May 17 (Box 31, Folder 715)
    - Roberts, Irene Roberts, John, 1953-64 (Box 31, Folder 716)
    - Rose, Billy, 1956 Feb 27 (Box 31, Folder 717)
    - Rothenberg, Albert, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 718-719)
      Letter of 1965 Apr 14 encloses copies
      of EO's will and autopsy report.
      See also: Drafts of letters, shorthand, in notebook #1, box 37 folder 828
    - Rubin, Jane
      See: Richard J. Madden Play Company, Inc., box 28, folder 670 through box 31, folder 713
    - Rulfo, Josephine, 1953, 1955, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 720)
    - Rutgers University Press, 1958 Mar 7 (Box 31, Folder 721)
    - "S", general (Box 31, Folder 722-723)
    - S. Fischer Verlag, 1955-64 (Box 31, Folder 724-725)
      Letter dated 1960 May 25 encloses two
      photographs of Stefani Hunzinger.
      Letter dated 1963 Feb 28 encloses
      photograph of Vienna production of The Straw.
    - Sabinson, Harvey, 1960 Feb 10 (Box 31, Folder 726)
    - Sadoff, Fred, 1961-63, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 727)
    - Sarlós, Robert Károly
      See: Drafts of letters, shorthand, in notebook #3, box 37, folder 830
    - Save the Children (U.S.), 1962-65, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 728)
      Letter dated 1962 Mar 29 encloses
      photograph of Floyd Galson.
    - Saxe, Serge, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 729)
    - Schmidt, Lars, 1956-62, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 730-732)
      Letter dated 1959 Dec 10 encloses
      nine photographs by Studio Lipnitzki
      of Paris production of Long Day's Journey Into Night.
    - Schuh, Oscar Fritz, 1957-64 (Box 32, Folder 733)
    - Seino, Choichiro, 1953-58 (Box 32, Folder 734)
    - Seldes, Marian, 1961-64, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 735)
      Letter dated 1964 Jul 8 encloses copy
      of photograph of EO standing with two
      men (ca. 192-).
    - Seymour, May Davenport
      See: Museum of the City of New York, box 25, folder 602
    - Shaktman, Ben, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 736)
    - Sheaffer, Louis, 1956-64, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 737-741)
      See also: Drafts of letters, shorthand, in notebook #3, box 37, folder 829
    - Shedd, Robert G., 1959 Aug 12 (Box 32, Folder 742)
    - Sherry Wine & Spirits Co., 1965 Apr 14 (Box 32, Folder 743)
    - Sherwood, Robert E., 1955 Apr 7 (Box 32, Folder 744)
    - Shoemaker, Ann, 1956 Nov 29 (Box 32, Folder 745)
    - Shyre, Paul, 1959-64, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 746)
    - Sinclair, Upton, [1957 Mar] (Box 32, Folder 747)
    - Sisk, Robert, 1953-62, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 748-750)
    - Sisson, John H., 1954-57 (Box 33, Folder 751)
    - Siu, R. G. H., 1956 (Box 33, Folder 752)
    - Stetson, Richard P., 1954-56 (Box 33, Folder 753)
    - Stierle, Hermann, 1958 (Box 33, Folder 754)
    - Straight, Beatrice, 1961 Feb 9 (Box 33, Folder 755)
    - Stroupe, John H., 1960 Jun 16 (Box 33, Folder 756)
    - Sze, Mai-Mai, 1957-62, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 757-758)
    - "T" general, 1954-61, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 759)
    - Talent Associates, 1960-61 (Box 33, Folder 760)
    - Teje, Tora, 1957 Nov 15 (Box 33, Folder 761)
    - This Week Magazine, 1956 Aug 8 (Box 33, Folder 762)
    - Throckmorton, Cleon, 1953 Dec 4 (Box 33, Folder 763)
    - Tidblad, Inga, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 764)
      Includes letter also signed by Lars
      Hanson.
    - Time (New York, N.Y.), 1957 Sep 12 (Box 33, Folder 765)
    - Tower, Benjamin C., 1955 (Box 33, Folder 766)
    - Traube, Shepard, 1956 May 16 (Box 33, Folder 767)
    - "U" general, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 768)
    - United States. Consulate General (Sao Paulo, Brazil), 1960 Feb 9 (Box 33, Folder 769)
    - University of California, Irvine. Library, 1955 (Box 33, Folder 770)
    - University of Delaware, 1956-57 (Box 33, Folder 771)
    - University of Richmond, [1958 Jan 27] (Box 33, Folder 772)
    - "V" general, 1955-59, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 773)
    - Van Lennep, William, 1958 Dec 16 (Box 33, Folder 774)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1955-65 (Box 33, Folder 775-777)
      Includes letters also signed by Fania
      Marinoff Van Vechten.
    - Van Vechten, Fania Marinoff, 1955 Sep 29 (Box 33, Folder 778)
      See also: Carl Van Vechten, box 33, folder 775-777
    - Verdon, Gwen, 1957 Jun 7 (Box 34, Folder 779)
    - Vincent Tailleur, Inc., 1960-65, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 780)
    - Voice of America (Organization), 1958 May 26 (Box 34, Folder 781)
    - "W" general, 1954-64, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 782)
    - Ward, Robert L., 1956-63, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 783-784)
    - Weatherby, William J., 1962-64 (Box 34, Folder 785)
    - Welton, Jean, 1954-65 (Box 34, Folder 786-787)
      Signs some letters "Marguerite."
    - White House (Washington, D.C.), 1962 (Box 34, Folder 788)
    - Whitehead, Robert, 1955-63, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 789)
    - Willis, William H., 1953 Nov 28 (Box 34, Folder 790)
    - Winther, Sophus Keith, 1954-55 (Box 34, Folder 791)
    - Wirth, Anita, 1964, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 792)
    - Wisniewski, Ray, 1960 Mar 14 (Box 34, Folder 793)
    - Wood, Jane, 1957-63 (Box 34, Folder 794)
    - "Y" general, [1953] (Box 34, Folder 795)
    - Yale School of Drama, 1957-63 (Box 34, Folder 796-798)
      Letter dated 1957 Oct 21 encloses
      photograph of masks.
    - Yale University. Dramatic Association, 1956, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 799)
    - Yale University. Library
      - Babb, James T., 1953-64, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 800-804)